Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XI: USSR/Independent States Files, 1983-1997
  - Moldova
    - Contacts, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Foreign Policy
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - United States, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Helsinki Watch Reports
      - General, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Moldova Report 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Laws
      - General, 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Drafts, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Minorities
      - General, 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Gagauz, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Russian, 1990-1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mission, 1992
      - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Notebooks, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Missions--Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Ombudsmen, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Politics
      - General, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Government Statements, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Press Clips, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Russian Army, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Trials
      - Notes, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - “Tiraspol 6” Trial, 1992-1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Moldova-Dniester Republic
      - Military, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Politics, 1991-1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Press Clips, 1987-1992, (3 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
      - Report-Helsinki Watch, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Nagorno-Karabakh
    - Air Bombings, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cease-Fire
      - Agreement, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Negotiations:, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Journalists, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Karabakh-Background, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Khojaly
      - General, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Victims List, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Kurds, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Nakhichevan, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Press Clips, 1988-1989, 1991-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
    - Press Releases, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Reports
      - Christian Solidarity International (CSI), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Human Rights Advocates, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Immigration and Naturalization Center, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Russia, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Turkey, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - United States--Foreign Policy, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Tajikistan:
    - Central Asia Bibliography, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Conferences and presentations, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Contacts in Tajikistan, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: Tajikistan, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - HRW Reports on Tajikistan, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - ICRC PRESS (International Committee of the Red Cross), 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Making Things Happen--Getting it Done 1996 Project Achievement Reports, Europe and the CIS, Regional Bureau for Europe and CIS, United Nations Development Programme, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Minority Rights Group Report: Tajikistan: A Forgotten Civil War by Nassim Jawad and Shahrbanou Tadjbakhsh, 1995 February (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Newswires and news clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Omri Daily Digest, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Reports from Dushanbe, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Refugees
      - Afghanistan--newspaper and clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Returnees, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Tajik and Afghan mission notebooks, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General, 1993-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - The Gharm Valley: Continued Tensions (draft manuscript edited by Milbert Shin), 1997 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - News clippings: FBIS and other news services, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - News service printouts re: Hostage taking, 1997 February-March, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Logistics, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Missions
      - Notes, 1993-1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Dushanbe--Notebooks, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - North Afghanistan--background information, 1993-1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Briefing materials prepared by the Soros Foundations, 1995, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
    - UNCHR Report, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - UN Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Uzbekistan free travel memorandum--United States, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Press
      - Accounts--Newspapers 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Clips, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Refugees, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Resource Page, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Tatarstan
    - Press Clips, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Ukraine
    - Independent Organizations--Ukrainian Committee “Helsinki-90”, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Press Clips, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Religion--Ukrainian Catholics, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - U.S.S.R.
    - Background
      - U.S.S.R.: Background, 1983-1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - U.S.S.R.: Background--Soviet Officials--Biographic Directory, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Censorship, 1983-1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Central Asia, 1990-1992 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Contacts, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Demonstrations, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Economy, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Elections (1989), 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Emigration Law, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Environment, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Federalism,1990 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Freedom of Movement, 1989-1992 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Germany
      - Ethnic Germans, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - German Unification, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail--Resignation, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Helsinki Groups, 1983-1991 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Human Rights, 1986-1991 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Khmara, Stepan, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Law
      - Dictionary, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Draft Legislation, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Media
      - Journalists--Directory, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Reform, 1989-1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Military, 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Minority Groups, 1989-1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Mirzayanov, Vil, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Moscow--Government
      - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Laws and Decrees, 1992-1995 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Statistics, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Moscow Memorial Group, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Moscow--Mission
      - Notes, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Notebooks, 1994-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
    - Moscow--Report--Discrimination 1992-1994, 1995, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - Policies
      - Nationalities, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Nuclear Arms Control, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Political Reform, 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Post-Coup Federation, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Press Clips
      - General, 1991-1993 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - General, 1994, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - General, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Prisoners of Conscience (POCs), 1988-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Prisons, 1989-1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Pyschiatric Abuses
      - General, 1989-1991 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - General, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - St. Petersburg, 1992-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - Visa Denials, 1987-1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - World Report, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Uzbekistan
    - Post-Coup, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Press Clips, 1989-1991 (Box 21, Folder 7)